DENET IGLESIAS BARO

Flat 43 Boyce House Aldrington Road London SW16 1UA

PERSONAL PROFILE

A motivated software engineer with over nine years' experience within technology consulting, banking systems, TV, radio, and IT security. Passionate about technology and regularly attend London tech sprint sessions. Able to quickly and effectively adapt to different technologies outside of current experience. Currently looking to resume professional career after moving to the UK and taking maternity leave. During this period has kept professional skills up to date through home studying and attending networking events.

KEY SKILLS

- Broad development knowledge, including JavaScript, HTML, CSS and JQuery.
- Good understanding of NodeJS, ReactJS, Redux and GraphQL.
- Industry aware and up to speed technically with current software development tools (Github, VSCode, Chrome Developer Tools, Slack, Jira).
- Excellent analytical and problem-solving skills.
- Effective team member and self-starter.
- Bi-lingual in English and Spanish.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Maternity Leave London, UK

August 2017 - present

Whilst on maternity leave I have been:

- Attending London technology sprint sessions
 - Hackathon weekly on Saturdays
 - Meet ups (LNUG, React girls, Node girls)
- Volunteering at the local South London Refugee Association.

Software Developer Everis Centers, Alicante, Spain Sept 2016 – July 2017

Everis are a Global Consulting firm. Developed high quality front-end code using AngularJS framework for an estate agent office application, Solvia Stores.

Worked with Java/J2EE on systems including a banking system for Bank Sabadell to enable loan and mortgage applications. Developed SOAP services, JSF views and managed the databases. JavaScript, AngularJS, Java/J2EE, Spring Framework, Spring Web Flow, JSF, SQL, CSS, Bootstrap, Web Services (REST/SOAP), SVN, GIT.

Web Developer Freelance, Madrid, Spain March 2016 - Sept 2016

Developed websites for an independent radio station, "Radio Encuentro". Analyzed, designed, deployed and gave post-production support.

Wordpress, Joomla, JavaScript, PHP

Software Engineer Sprintfinal S.A., Madrid, Spain Oct 2011 – March 2016

Sprintfinal is an advertising agency. Worked in a team to develop internal systems for Bank Santander. Performed detailed analysis of business requirements and developed comprehensive plans defining and scoping project requirements.

Created specific software and devised testing scenarios to ensure optimum levels of efficiency to develop internal Bank Santander systems.

PHP, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, CSS, MySQL, Wordpress, Zend, Bootstrap.

IT Security Leader ICRT, Havana, Cuba Aug 2009 – Sept 2011

Led IT Security department for a Cuban TV Station, managing a team of four.

Developed applications for the best administrative performance of the TV Station. Wrote documentation for the applications and procedures to be followed in case of malware attacks. *C#. Joomla.*

Software Developer Segurmatica, Havana, Cuba Sept 2007 – July 2009

Cuban computer security consulting firm. Researched and developed tools for automatic processing and analysis of malwares. Part of the team responsible for creating and releasing the antivirus updates.

C++, Visual Basic.

EDUCATION

Master's Degree, Informatics: Interaction and Multimedia

September 2011 – June 2014 Rey Juan Carlos University, Madrid, Spain

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

September 2002 – July 2007 Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science, University of Havana, Cuba

INTERESTS

Reading, Travelling, Yoga, Mindfulness.

REFERENCES

References are available upon request.

CONTACT

Mobile: 07424 218127

Email: denet.iglesias@gmail.com

Nationality: Cuban

Visa status: Married to Spanish national. I have a UK residence card and can work freely

Github: github.com/thenet84

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/deiglesias